duoboots.com 2018-08-30

# Privacy Policy | DuoBoots

#### 1\. PRIVACY OF YOUR INFORMATION

#### 2\. TRANSACTION SECURITY

#### 3\. COOKIES

#### 4\. CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

### 1\. PRIVACY OF YOUR INFORMATION

DuoBoots is committed to protecting any personal information that you may provide to us and we believe it is important for you to know how we treat information about you that we may receive from this website. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully as it explains what information DuoBoots collects from you and how we use this information, including setting out the circumstances where we could provide it to third parties. You should also read the separate Terms and Conditions of Sale here.

**What information do we collect?**

Should you choose to take advantage of some of our services and or to buy any of our products, we will collect personal information about you during this process, such as your email address, name and address, and credit card details.

• Should you choose to register to receive DuoBoots marketing emails, we will collect your name, email address and country . We may also collect mobile numbers for SMS updates and date of birth for birthday offers. These items of information are optional and require your consent to use. We will send marketing emails a couple of times a week, however all subscribers have the option to join a monthly newsletter or unsubscribe at any time.

• Should you choose to take part in DuoBoots competitions, prize draws or questionnaires/surveys we will collect your name, email address and mailing address, and we will also collect the answers to all questions asked

• Should you provide a friend’s email address via our ‘Tell a Friend’ feature, we will collect your name and email address, and the addresses and message that you input, solely to deliver this information to the intended recipients. This information will not be used for any other purpose. 

Even if you do not register or buy with us, we may also collect, and our third party providers of advertisements and content may collect, information about where you are on the internet (e.g. the website address you came from, IP address, domain types) and technical information such as your browser type and the pages of the DuoBoots website you viewed during your visit.

• Like most websites, our servers automatically record the page requests made when you visit our sites. These “server logs” typically include your web request, IP address, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser.

 **What do we do with the information we collect?**

• All of the information we collect will be stored on secure servers, and treated as completely confidential.

• We will use the information which we collect to help us to administer our website, improve the usefulness and effectiveness of our website, to personalise your experience on our website, to help you log on in future and to continue to use our website. We may also use the information we collect to deliver appropriate content or advertising to you on the DuoBoots website or third party websites. By knowing your preferences we can deliver relevant information that meets your needs and ensures that your visit to our site is quick, easy and productive. We use a technology known as cookies to manage this process. For more information on how we use cookies, click [here](https://duoboots.com/pages/cookie-policy).

• We will use your personal details to process your order, respond to your enquiries, and inform you of the status of your order.

• Only if you have given express consent to allow us to do so when registering or buying with us, we may use your information to communicate with you through post, sms or email to notify you of new products, competitions, special offers and relevant service information. If you have subscribed to our emails in the past and would prefer not to receive emails from duoboots.com in the future, simply click on the unsubscribe link that can be found at the bottom of all weekly emails to opt out. (UK DuoBoots mail order: +44 (0)330 100 3455).

• We may pass your personal information to third parties who help us to maintain, administer or develop our website, or help us to provide the products available on our website. If so, that information is only given to those third parties for that limited purpose.

• If you provide express permission for us to do so when signing up for your account on the DuoBoots website, we may use your data, or permit selected third parties to use your data, to provide you with information about products and services which may be of interest to you and we or they may contact you about these by post, phone or email. If you do not provide this permission at the point of account creation or purchase, or in your account settings at a later date, we will never use your data in this way. If we do disclose personal information to third parties, we will only do so to third parties whom we are satisfied have measures to protect your personal information in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy.

• Reputable third-party banking and distribution institutions handle our payment transactions and order delivery. They receive the information needed to verify and authorise your payment for purchases made on this website, and to process and deliver your order. All such organisations are under strict obligation to keep your personal information private, and will only ever use your information for the above purposes.

• You should be aware that if we are requested by the police or any other regulatory or government authority investigating suspected illegal activities to provide your Personal Information and /or User Information, we are entitled do so.

• When entering any of our competitions or prize draws, you provide your name, email address, and country mailing address and answers to 10 ‘profiling questions’ which are designed to provide you with a relevant and personalised experience with the DuoBoots website and emails. If you win the competition or prize draw, we will send the prize to the address entered and notify you by email. When you enter the competition or prize draw, you are also included in our marketing email list to receive promotions, new products, and new additions to the website. You may unsubscribe from this subscription list by following the instructions in any email received.

 • When providing a friend’s email address via our ‘Tell a Friend’ feature, we will collect your name and email address, and the addresses and message that you input, solely to deliver this information to the intended recipients. This information will not be used for any other purpose.

• As DuoBoots is an international company, there may be occasions where information may be transferred from one country to another.

**Your consent**

• In the course of registering and using our website and any services/products offered via our website, certain personal information about you will be captured electronically or otherwise and transmitted to DuoBoots, and potentially to any third parties as set out in this Privacy Policy.

• We may transfer your personal information from one country to another for processing or use in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

• By using our website, you expressly agree to the collection and use of your personal information as set out above for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy.

• You consent to DuoBoots contacting you in the ways outlined in this privacy policy, whether by telephone, e-mail, sms or in writing, and you confirm that you do not and will not consider any of this contact as being a breach of any of your rights under the EU General Data Protection Regulation 2018 (GDPR).

• If you do not want us to use your personal data for marketing purposes or to pass your details on to third parties for marketing purposes, please do not tick the relevant boxes situated in the account creation and purchasing process, displayed to you before placing an order. If you have previously given permission for us to use your data for marketing purposes, and wish to revoke this permission, please use the unsubscribe link within any of DuoBoots’ marketing emails, or contact [contactus@duoboots.com](mailto:contactus@duoboots.com) to make this request.

• If you do not want to accept cookies you will be unable to use some of this website’s features, as they depend technically on the use of cookie technology. Find out more about how to block cookies in our cookie policy [here](https://duoboots.com/pages/cookie-policy).

• If you'd like to opt out of behavioural advertising cookies, please go to the Network Advertising Initiative website - <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp> –. (Please note that we're not responsible for the content of external websites).

**Accessing your information**

If you want to access or update any of your personal information held by DuoBoots, you can amend or update your profile online in the My Account section of the website here. To completely remove your details from our database, or to request cessation of contact from DuoBoots, or for any enquiries relating to your personal information or profile with DuoBoots, please contact us at [contactus@duoboots.com](mailto:contactus@duoboots.com).

DuoBoots reserves the right to access and disclose personal information to comply with applicable laws and lawful government requests, to operate its systems properly, or to protect itself or its users.

  **How long we keep your personal data**

We’ll only hold your information for as long as you are a customer. If you haven’t opened an email in 12 months, we will make attempts to ask you whether you wish to continue subscribing. If you do not respond after this period, you will be unsubscribed and you will be removed from our email database.

If you no longer wish to receive our emails, you can also contact our Customer Care team and request us to delete all your personal details.

**Access to information**

You have the right to request access to any personal information we hold about you, along with the right to request the update of information, or to request us to delete it.

You also have the right to complain to your data protection regulator.

If you wish to exercise any of your rights, have a complaint, or would like more information, please contact us.

### 2\. TRANSACTION SECURITY

DuoBoots respects the privacy of its customers and is committed to complying with all laws relating to the protection of personal data.

To prevent unauthorised access, we follow appropriate security procedures in the storage and disclosure of personal information which you have given to us.

Certain areas of our website are password protected. You can help to preserve your privacy by never sharing your password with anyone else, or by using a secure password which contains a mixture of lower and upper case letters, along with numbers.

Our order processing environment features several widely accepted and endorsed security methods to ensure that transactions, ordering and fulfilment are entirely safe and that all exchange of information remain confidential. Credit cards details are processed through separate merchant services vendors. We encrypt your credit card information to ensure your orders remain private and protected as they travel across the Internet.

We accept orders only from web browsers that permit communication through Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology. This means you cannot inadvertently place an order through an unsecured connection.

You can tell whether a page is secure as 'https' will replace the 'http' at the front of www.duoboots.com in your browser address window.

Your payment details are held in an encrypted format until we process your order. If you have any questions regarding our credit card security policies please contact us at [contactus@duoboots.com](mailto:contactus@duoboots.com).

### 3\. COOKIES

**How DuoBoots uses cookies**

Our website, as with many others, attempts to place a small data file (known as a “cookie”) onto your computer for several purposes, including in order to expedite your navigation throughout the website or to enable you to return to a purchase if disconnected, to record user preferences, to record your usage of our website in order to improve the site, or to serve content tailored specifically for you. We may use cookies to store your personal information for promotional or marketing purposes. We use cookies to improve the quality of our service.

DuoBoots will never disclose any information gathered from cookies to any third parties. All data passed by cookies is anonymous and will never contain your name, address, telephone number, email address, IP address or any payment details.

If you prefer not to accept cookies, you can set your browser to reject them or to alert you before one is placed. The Help menu on the menu bar of most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie and how to disable cookies altogether. You can also get useful information on what cookies are and how to control your browser’s cookie settings at the following website: [http://www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) (Please note that we're not responsible for the content of external websites).

 **Third party cookies**

DuoBoots uses cookies to help third party advertisers and publishers serve and manage DuoBoots -related adverts across the web. In this way, we use cookies to display a particular advert to a particular visitor based on that visitor’s past browsing activity on the DuoBoots website.

DuoBoots works with third party ad servers and ad networks who serve DuoBoots advertisements on our behalf. DuoBoots will not disclose your personal details to any third parties. All data collected is anonymous and will not contain your name, address, telephone number, email address or IP address.

These third parties may place anonymous cookies in your browser so that they can collect browsing data (such as the products you have viewed). These cookies will allow the third party to serve advertisements containing products that you have looked at and similar products.

Advertisements will always include a link to the third party privacy policy page that will include information for users on how to opt-out of being cookie retargeted. If you wish to opt out of receiving such advertisements, or if you would like to receive more information on why you are being retargeted, simply click the 'i' which appears in the top left hand corner of every advertisement.

Another way that you can opt out of behavioural advertising cookies is to go to the Network Advertising Initiative website and opt out of any active cookies that you can see are stored on your computer - <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp> ( Please note that we're not responsible for the content of external websites).

For more detail on the third party ad networks with whom we currently work, please see our full cookie policy here.

 **DuoBoots' cookie policy**

For more detail about what cookies are, DuoBoots' own cookie policy, what cookies DuoBoots uses, what third party cookies DuoBoots employs, information about how to manage cookies on your computer, and information on how DuoBoots uses cookies to deliver banner advertising on other websites, please see our full cookie policy [here](https://duoboots.com/pages/cookie-policy).

### 4\. CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

We reserve the right to add to or change the terms of this privacy policy at our sole discretion, without prior notice to you. If we change this privacy policy, we will post the new policy on our website, and it will become effective from the time of posting to our website. Please visit our website on a regular basis to make sure you have read the latest version of our privacy policy and you understand what we do with your personal information. Whenever possible, we will give you notice of any changes prior to their implementation. Your continued use of our website following the posting of changes to these terms means that you consent to those changes.

Questions regarding this policy should be directed as follows:  
Customer Care, DuoBoots, Vallis House, Vallis Road, Frome, Somerset. BA11 3EG.
